hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah kurkowski and if you haven't
listened this podcast before this is for
coaches trainers authors speakers course
graders to know how to grow their
business get more customers and use
social media direct response marketing
to get more results now today i had the
privilege of introducing you to one of
my friends as well as somebody that
we've done business with over the past
year
david willis he's from southeast texas
he's a pastor he's a worship leader he's
a speaker a coach a trainer and somebody
that really knows how to challenge you
and challenge your way of thinking in a
way that's unique that honestly i bet
you've never seen before so help me
welcome david willis how are you doing
today david hey
hey i'm doing well i'm doing well thanks
for having me on yeah
i was excited when you wrote to me and
were like hey you want to do a podcast
i'm like yes let's do it
yes so you're you're somebody who has
kinda and you just got started making
social media content last year didn't
you yes towards the end of last year
around august uh made the decision just
to
get rid of all the excuses and go all in
and start posting about a video every
single day and trying to do a video
a picture and a quote like every single
day that's awesome and and that's what i
tell people to do when they get started
to build their community
to post every single day what kind of
effect and impact did that have for you
was it worth it did you see results
immediately
or what happened for you how did you get
there
sure so for me i went into it with the
foresight fortunately of it's going to
take about
90 days three months something like that
to really start picking out a pattern
and then once you pick out a pattern
then you can start kind of niching down
a little bit but for me
it took about 90 days to start seeing
traction on all of my posts
but then
sometime around the beginning of the
year i started seeing most of my reels
pop off to a couple thousand views every
single day which equated to about you
know 25
up to 30 000 views a week
which i'm not a actual i don't have a
huge channel a huge instagram following
a huge tick tock following i'm about
under 1500 on both facebook and
instagram and yet i was reaching you
know 30 000 people a week at the
beginning of this year into now i've
seen steady growth over that time
more more rapid growth in tick tock but
i've been cross posting everything
and
yeah it seems steady growth and i've
seen results not only in
what i've tried to drive traffic to
which is like my songs and music and
just having conversations with people
but even with people who have been
difference makers in my life you know
you
a guy named rick pino some other guys
who've reached out to me basically
through the content that i was making
really helped bridge the gap uh between
where i was and where i feel like i'm
going so just in the discipline
and in the results it's been connection
with the right people just by doing the
discipline the day-to-day and putting
stuff out there
i have a question for you because you're
you're you're a christian i'm a
christian
tick-tock is kind of a dark place sure
like it like it doesn't fit into our
mold of like uh maybe this is where we
should hang out
what would you say that because i have a
lot of people that listen to me that are
coaches they want to have an impact but
they they don't want to be on tick tock
and and while that's their personal
choice maybe some encouragement because
i actually think that it is a good thing
to be on there just maybe some
encouragement for them
yeah so the cool thing is i started
cross posting on tick tock about two
months after i started everywhere else
kind of for the same reasons like i
didn't want to be on tick tock i'd heard
some things even when i had popped up on
there with people share me links or
whatever it would like go to things that
i wouldn't want to watch all this kind
of stuff
and then someone said the most profound
thing to me is that it's an algorithm
and if you don't want to watch something
you can tell it to not show you this and
then you can move on essentially and you
train the algorithm on your feed on tick
tock on what you want to consume
but the whole mindset for social media
for me started to shift around that time
august september october of last year
that i i shifted from being a consumer
of social media media to being a creator
of social media and for me it wasn't
that i'm sitting there scrolling through
tick-tock all the time scrolling through
instagram all the time scrolling through
facebook but i am contributing and
engaging with my content that you know
and tick-tock has been one of the places
where more people probably interact with
you on tick tock than facebook or
instagram and yes it can be kind of a
dark place but honestly i've had some
pretty decent conversations with people
in comment threads and responses and
stuff like that that have given me a
little bit of hope of like okay maybe
there's some uh meaningful interactions
that can be had on this platform and
that's kind of the goal right is i want
to have meaningful interactions with
people uh even if it's in
a dark place
explain what meaningful means to you
let's unpack that word a little bit yeah
so i guess that could be a little bit
subjective because it all depends on
your
uh goal or purpose of social media you
need a goal or purpose of social media
for me there's a couple of different
layers deep for me
for people right there yeah you need to
have a goal you've got your posting
first hand absolutely in a dream you
know it can be just a dream you know it
doesn't have to be this like really
five-point plan of like oh i'm gonna get
them in my funnel through social media
it may not be like that but it could be
that for me it's about
um can i reach people for god i mean i'm
a lot of my com my posts are about uh
you know talking about biblical
principles and talking about some things
that i've learned in my own life that
could help somebody maybe through a
challenging season or a challenging time
and so some of those meaningful
interactions for me have been times when
someone's commented not just the oh that
was good thumbs up but when they're like
hey i have a question about this or i
disagree about this because disagreement
if someone took the time to watch your
video or your post and then disagrees
with you in a in a respectful way maybe
not in a in a hater type of way but in a
respectful way i want to engage with
them because that is a meaningful
interaction and i can learn a lot from
that feedback it could be that i was
presenting it wrong it could be that
they've had their own experiences and
were had some trauma or hurt or past or
anything like that or it could be
somewhere in the middle and just by
engaging with them as a real human on
the other side there have been some cool
moments where i've even taken some of
those conversations offline so maybe a
phone call or something like that
and for me that's a meaningful
conversation now that could mean
different for your business or your
brand it could be that hey i'm having a
meaningful conversation in a dm where
someone is actually wanting to pursue
business with me or wants to learn more
about my product or my brand or whatever
but it's like how can we get them to
take a next step with us
me you whoever's doing this or whoever's
watching this so that you can then
interact with them beyond just the
screen the screen is just to get their
attention the scroll is just to get
their attention it's just the
introduction hey you most of the people
who watch my reels and watch my tick
tocks don't actually follow me on
instagram or or tick tock and some of
them are it's the first time they're
actually seeing me so it's just an
introduction
that's why bite-sized content is so
important and kind of universally
applicable content on on your niche or
whatever is important you know just
getting out there and saying hey i'm
here let's have a conversation
in the comments and dm and a share or
whatever you can interact with them in a
very meaningful way that goes beyond
just the original post
i love that and i'm going to come back
to that in a second because i think we
need to talk about even more on on what
you just said right there but i want to
ask you this a lot of people who listen
and they're listening to you right now
they see my social media they can follow
you where can they follow you as well
online you can follow me at david willis
co
everywhere that's on instagram facebook
tick tock youtube david willis co it's
all one word no periods or spaces or
dashes put it on the screen here there
you go so here's my question is
people always said there's two things i
don't know what to say
sure
and i don't have the time to come up
with what to say
yeah and so it's those two things and
and they've heard the training they know
that they should be posting and it's and
and and yet month after month after
month maybe they get one video up a
month and that's it and they're they're
overwhelmed by
just
not sure is it am i saying the right
thing is it connecting what if this
doesn't connect with somebody what
happens then how would you help
that person who's
overthinking over analyzing or maybe
they just they want to have such a
spirit of excellence because i know that
you you're about that so much
they want to have that spirit of
excellence and it's keeping them from
really doing that because of all the
responsibilities that they have in their
life how would you encourage that person
maybe even some tips and strategies that
you have
yeah so i'll speak to the busyness
aspect first uh so i'm a father of four
i've been married for 13 years i have a
full-time job in ministry which is more
than 40 hours a week it's probably more
like 60 plus
with weekends and nights too as well so
i understand busy and when i got the
sort of conviction if you will to start
posting that was my first reaction to
when am i going to have time to do this
just apart from what am i going to say
so the first the first thought in my
mind was i need to become more
disciplined and more efficient like
those two things really speak to me as a
person that's my personality comes a
little bit more naturally to me i
understand that it may not come
naturally to other people but there's
tons of resources out there to help you
become more disciplined and more
efficient the first one discipline
there's a great book by james clear
called atomic habits this was a book
that i discovered later after i was
doing all this actually was doing the
stuff in the book before i actually
realized what it was and that book kind
of gave me more language and permission
to keep pursuing it basically the crux
of all of this is create structures and
habits and systems in your life that
will give you more time to focus on
these things and that might be waking up
a little earlier might be staying up a
little later maybe you're a night owl
and you get energized at night for me i
was very aware that the hours of
like six p six a.m to like eight a.m or
like my prime time i can go as soon as i
wake up i have a lot of energy and i
have a lot of creative space too as well
and so that's the time that i set aside
i got the i got really jealous for that
time to spend creating either social
media posts or writing songs i write
songs too as well or doing anything
creative that requires a lot of that
sort of part of my brain for you it
might be in the in like 2 a.m some
people are night owls some people are
during the middle of the day after lunch
they like to you know create or write or
whatever find that about yourself and
then maximize that time some some of you
you might wake up a little earlier stay
up a little late or take a longer lunch
or on some days you bring your lunch to
work with you and then you just sit at
your desk and you create while you're
eating your lunch you know all these
types of different things find time in
your day
to to pull out those 30 minutes 15
minutes i mean real honestly a lot of
this stuff is about 30 minutes a day
maybe an hour at first but then the goal
is to get more efficient with it find
where you're you're getting stuck in
your process and just start getting more
efficient for me it was i needed to
start batch recording because if i if i
got in a routine with it and i got into
a rhythm with it i could knock out five
or six videos in two three hours versus
an hour each day but i record them with
the light and with the camera and a
microphone you could do it with your
phone just throughout the day or
whatever but for me it's discipline and
efficiency that was sort of what helped
me uh find the time uh because i was
finding time to watch tv in the evenings
i was finding time to go to starbucks
and you know get a coffee that takes me
30 minutes to get in line and everything
like that i bought an espresso machine
so that i can make coffee at home and so
it wouldn't take me that long to go to
the store and get coffee you know i'm
finding ways to free up my time so that
i can spend it uh
creating because in the morning i would
go get coffee well that's a 15 minute
trip to the store another 10 minutes to
get my coffee another 15 minute back
that's 35 minutes on the way to work
that's my prime time that's when i'm
most creative i'm spending it driving
why would i do that you know and so
finding those moments that i am most
creative and maximizing those through
efficiency and then discipline too as
well
okay here's a question i have on that
this is kind of a secondary question
you know i have a lot of people who have
listed my podcast and they're they're
they're they're they're artists they're
minded they're not as logical
they're more that and you're a
songwriter so you're also an artist
yes they just like i have never been
disciplined in my life or efficient and
i don't think there's anything i can do
to ever change that about myself what
would you say to that start small
for me one of the things that i did at
the beginning of this year because i
knew i needed to start growing in some
discipline was i i started taking some
of the steps in this book atomic habits
one of them was like create habit
stacking and all this kind of stuff well
this is a silly example but i needed to
get into a good skincare routine so what
i did was i set out my
moisturizer and my
face wash right beside my toothbrush so
before i go to brush my teeth i'm forced
with seeing the moisturizer and
face wash so i wash my face put on
lotion and then brush my teeth and it
was it's creating a trigger for me to
remember to do this step um there's
other things i do throughout like
vitamins and taking all this kind of
stuff anyways but the point is like
create for yourself a system
or a structure that makes discipline
easier uh if it means that you know
you're waking up later
because you keep hitting your snooze
well put your phone on the other side of
the room and if you aren't disciplined
enough to do that then start by you know
getting a louder alarm clock or you know
start by giving yourself some kind of
incentive uh we all work a little bit
differently as far as what
drives us to uh
desire or action or whatever
and so for me it was starting small with
getting in the habit of doing the
moisturizer and the face wash and all
this kind of stuff and then it was well
if i can do that i can wake up a little
earlier and the way i do that is i go to
bed a little bit earlier so i'm putting
the remote down i'm putting my phone on
a lock where it turns off
basically at like 11 o'clock so i'm not
scrolling afterwards
um just taking little steps starts to
build your confidence and james clear
talks about this in his book about every
action you take is a vote for the person
you want to become so as you take those
actions towards being a more disciplined
person you're voting for that person in
your life you might say up to this point
i've been voting for the undisciplined
kind of whimsical person who is just
inspired all the time or maybe i'm just
i'm caught up in all these different
things and i don't know what my day is
going to look like and we'll just start
taking small
actions that then vote for the right
person that you want to become you know
so that's a great book by the way listen
to it on your commute um it's not very
dense like it's it's actually more
practical than it is theoretical so you
can kind of listen through it really
quickly and get the majority of what
they're taught what he's talking about
so that's so good and something i would
add to that is you know
we we prioritize what is truly important
to us absolutely and sometimes we've
never looked at our priorities to say am
i making this a priority am i making
being on call
for
my sister-in-law more important than
taking care of my health for example
that somebody would do that and then say
oh i have no time because they're always
taking care of answering their
sister-in-law instead of saying hey i'm
available for you during this time not
all these times and having boundaries on
our time as well is so important
yeah good like your boundaries
henry mcleod's book boundaries that was
that's a good segue because actually
that was a precursor reading that book
implementing those principles
really helped become a precursor to me
getting more disciplined in life
because i
started setting boundaries started
becoming more efficient with my time my
time was my time you know now i have a
family i have four kids i have a wife i
have a job and of course like there's a
lot that has to go on with that how do
you balance that
well i know balance is a myth
like the idea of everything being
perfectly balanced is a myth that's why
i like batch recording um because i know
most most weeks i have
a block of time of about two hours for
my life not everybody's life is this way
where i can
dedicate to this now i didn't have that
before but i i've set it aside now for
myself uh because of the way my life is
structured i have a day off that i can
do that uh i know not everybody has that
so for me it was about even even like
early on when i didn't have that day off
and i was working even more hours a week
i i got up an hour earlier than my
family and i i used that time back then
to study the bible and that was my time
with god
but it could just as easily you know 30
minutes of that and then 30 minutes of
content creation uh because it really
only takes about 30 minutes a day um
honestly like i mean the time you're
you're posting tapped into something
powerful
yeah and so if you can't find time
create time uh that goes back to the
discipline aspect of waking up a little
earlier or going to bed a little earlier
or taking your lunch with you to work so
you don't have to commute to go grab
something to eat uh maximizing those
times because like you said a minute ago
we make time for what's important to us
what is priority in our life we find
time for i was finding time to watch tv
right i knew about all the upcoming
shows i knew
what movies were out i was finding time
to go to the movies i was finding time
to play video games and all this kind of
stuff and you know
if we if we really want something in
life there are times when we have to
make sacrifices and change in order to
experience change in other areas of our
life hey you want to grow in your
business you want to have change in your
business find change somewhere else in
your life that you can then funnel into
the business so for me it was hey i'm
getting serious about content creation
i'm getting serious about writing music
i'm getting serious about building that
audience in that community so i'm going
to change these aspects of my life so
that i can change these other aspects of
my life so
that's so good and something to that
there's a life hack that i've done for a
while if i'm wanting to get disciplined
in something specifically around time
is i actually uh it goes against most of
the productivity teaching that's on the
planet today it's like okay do the hard
thing first some people have to do that
personalities like myself i actually
train myself by doing the fun thing
first yes so so what i do is to what
motivated me to get up at 4 am
is i i would play my video games when i
got up at 4am
and then i would do some writing at 4am
and get that out of the way and that way
i had a motivation to get up early and i
wasn't waiting until later in the day to
go play
i was actually doing it first and then
that ended up setting me up to where the
rest of my day i actually had more time
because i hacked my motivation to get up
earlier to do something fun
yes and if you're excited about
something you know it's funny you
mentioned like something like that you
know
if you've ever gone on a trip and your
flight is so early that you have to get
to the airport at like
5 a.m 4 00 a.m and you're like well i
don't even usually wake up at this time
but because you're going on a vacation
or a trip you are more than happy to
wake up at 3 30 in the morning 4 a.m in
the morning so you can go stand in a
security line so that you can get on a
plane so you can land in cancun in the
afternoon
so it's it's your motivation is crucial
there and sometimes honestly your
motivation can be pain it's of pain
avoidance like i'm i'm gonna avoid the
pain of having my business fail so i'm
gonna have motivation to do good things
my pastor says it like this sometimes we
don't change until we hurt enough to
change
but when pain comes into the equation
like i'm losing business i'm losing
clients i'm i'm losing customers and i'm
losing employees even i have to change
something and so that can be a
motivation too as well but i love
starting with the fun thing first
because it does it sets your motivation
right throughout the day of like you get
excited you take ownership of the day um
and so it's time for people to do that
it's time for you watching to do that
you got to change something in your life
so you can change something else in your
life
yeah here's something huge i'm going to
kind of bring this all together as well
about social media so
we talked about
how to set aside time to make social
media we talked about that social media
is specifically to promote
yourself i see a lot of people that i
think have the wrong focus on social
media they're trying to change the world
and and change other people through
their social media content and they're
trying so hard to make it the perfect
most
impactful piece of content when really
their focus should just be to get
attention to promote and to talk about
what they're doing and so talk about
that as well a lot of people they get
stuck on what should i do what are the
best practices you know
i feel called by god to impact people
and so if i'm not focused on impacting
people on social media then i'm being
disobedient to god and they come up with
these reasons why they all work up
something in their head i've seen it
i've heard it from hundreds of people i
struggled with these exact same reasons
myself
a couple years ago what would you say to
that as far as as far as what to say on
social media and that it's social media
content is more for promotion to the
other things that you have rather than
the the meat that you give people
well in what you're saying is so true
because it is that kind of introduction
to you it's and and just remembering the
fact that
especially on tick tock and instagram
this is a momentary piece of content
youtube podcast sometimes facebook but
mostly youtube and podcasts are
evergreen
you will you will search for it you'll
go back and reference it you'll go back
and watch it
instagram and tick tock and sometimes
facebook that's a moment twit twitter's
that way too tweet you know tweets you
know sometimes tweets go viral and you
can reference them later but most the
time it's an in the moment conversation
it's like a text message you don't think
that much when you're sending a text
message even to a person you've never
met before you just go hey i'm david you
know i'd like to meet you for coffee or
something like that and that's as simple
as it has to be
sometimes social media we over
complicate it because we think it's
somehow going to impact our brand in 15
20 years but honestly that kind of
interaction is so momentary and then
it's gone like i don't know like when
people like my stuff from like a month
ago i'm like that is weird like you did
something on my page to go find that
content like it didn't show up in your
feed like your feed is
maybe less than a week old tic toc is
probably even shorter than that you know
and and so i wouldn't worry too much
about
am i crafting the perfect post because
you don't even have the data that tells
you what to post yet because there you
go 90 days maybe 100 days which when i
say that i mean 90 posts i mean 90 days
of consistently posting every single day
that shows you your trends that shows
you your data you can read uh tons of
articles about when the best time to
post is what to post about all this kind
of stuff but until you take action on it
yourself and do the research for your
own audience and how you do you
you don't even know what's most
effective for you for me it's
8 30 to 9 30 on tuesdays are my most
popular
times to do posts and for me it's like a
45 second talking head uh video to my
camera and if i don't cut the camera
every three seconds or whatever to zoom
in or whatever then i'm gonna lose
people but i knew that after watching
10 of my posts pop off more about 15 20
percent more than the other ones and i
go what was different about this post
not necessarily the content because i i
say almost very similar things
throughout every post i mean don't be
afraid of repetition but what was it
about this
that was special and and then start
honing it in a little bit more so this
is not a
oh my gosh if i get it wrong one time
it's going to be with me forever this is
a kind of a trial and error experiment
marketing is kind of like that too as
well where you're sending out an ad and
you're split testing it and you're doing
this email and that email and your trial
and you're dialing it in it's never
never gonna be perfect the first time
and for perfectionists like myself
that's a hard thing because you over
analyze
and then in over analyzing you over plan
and then over planned you become
overwhelmed and then when you get
overwhelmed you start to
self-doubt and then try to hide and then
i never get anything done and then you
over analyze and then you over you know
all this kind of stuff again and again
and again but action breaks the
hesitation cycle every single
time if you just start taking a little
bit of action i'm gonna post and i'm
gonna talk about the thing that i love
to talk about most about my business
maybe it's maybe it's as simple as you
are a t-shirt design business and you
love when the ink dries on the on the uh
the shirt for the first time and it's
like that
you know from canvas blank to all of a
sudden the design you know that moment
right there you love that just talking
about that for 20 seconds and that's
your post that's your first post just
talk about what you love about your
business
that's an introduction to who you are
and what you love about doing what you
do
and
just keep getting just keep doing keep
putting your reps in and then you can
find out later
what was the perfect post out of the 90
that you made
there was one that was probably better
than all the other ones or two maybe you
know a one to two percent outlier find
those and then start narrowing down what
was different about those but you need
data and that gives you an uh you know
when i found that out
man it really freed me up from having to
look every single moment of every single
day you know did that one do well that
one did better than the one yesterday oh
but the next one just did worse than all
three of them combined you know but you
know pay attention to when people
comment and reply back for sure
but don't worry about the results for at
least like 90 days like just give it
some time to simmer all you need to
worry about is consistency that's all
you got to worry about so you know you
were asking about you know how do you
how do you get out of am i crafting the
perfect post my perfectionism is not
letting me do this how do i make an
impact just start get the reps in make
the introduction talk about what you
love
and get consistent with it that's so
awesome i want to ask you this so for me
my pattern across my social media
content it keeps coming back to content
about
boundaries and not caring about what
haters think because for coaches and
trainers those are the two i think
things that they struggle with and so
every time i talk about those it's like
the posts go crazy um
it's amazing what was what was your like
pattern message that really you ended up
finding like worked for you you promote
your your music right and i tell people
this
i don't teach about boundaries or
dealing with haters but that's my
content that draws in for what i teach
what's yours
so so the
base of my
product brand or whatever is of course
music i write christian music i write
worship music just praising god that
kind of stuff and in in my consistent
message you know there's always
something talking about god a principle
i've learned and walking with him and
all this kind of stuff but one of the
things i found most consistently helps
people
is is kind of the same message that
we're talking about with a with a
christian perspective which is
not giving up on god not giving up on
his plan for your life keep moving
forward i often say this the exit ramps
come quickly and they come often but you
have to stay on the highway in order to
get where you're going you can always
find a reason to exit you got a flat
tire you you know you're not really
you're tired you're not ready to to go
to the next place you can always find an
exit ramp but here's the deal if you
keep moving forward you'll get where
you're going
so that's kind of the message that i
find i i'm more that's awesome freer to
release i guess i should say you know
it's more something i can i can really
talk about with passion and that's the
other thing as you keep doing this i
find myself saying things that i'm like
oh wow
i didn't know that was in there and i
didn't realize i was passionate about
helping people stay on the highway and
not take the exit ramp
i didn't know i was passionate about
that until i started talking about it so
even in the midst of all the things
you're posting find the things that are
just more fun to talk about for yourself
because when you do that when you're
being you and being authentic you know
don't worry so much about what it you
know what are what is the market saying
i should post about or what is this you
don't even know that yet just just talk
about you and talk about what makes you
happy you talk about what you're
passionate about because
that human interaction
translates so much better over camera
than just talking about what you think
the market wants you to talk about
just like what you were saying like you
you do coaching and training and in
teach and train coaches how to be good
coaches and you train guys how to do
marketing and all this kind of stuff but
talking about boundaries
is an implicit part of that
but it makes you it makes you come alive
in your conversation because you have a
history there and then it invites people
into that conversation and you can help
them in a different way than even your
coaching does and so it's such a
powerful tool you know that's what i
mean when i said earlier about a
meaningful interaction just
something like that kind of makes the
whole thing special you know
i wrote down in my notes when we were
talking
you actually texted me too as well and
this is perfect for this
how do you talk to people online without
being boring or cheesy that was so that
was a topic that you sent in that you
wanted to talk about and i think
like that's the perfect like kind of
next thing to just share what are some
of your thoughts on that
so
everyone has
just sort of the general idea of what
their content
should be about you know like let's say
for example you have a weight loss
business then fitness kind of has this
whole natural ecosystem of dieting and
exercise and you know discipline and all
this types of stuff and so uh i followed
a guy who said something like content
buckets whenever you're talking about a
topic let's say for example for me
it's it's christian living or
following god well in that there's tons
of things that are like sub categories
and if you take maybe 10 minutes fine i
always tell people this go find your
favorite park
that you feel most relaxed at maybe
overlooking a lake or some children
playing or just some a good good moment
take your notebook
right on the top of it your general idea
branding
fitness
christian living and then underneath
that like a subheading subcategories
dieting and exercise dot no split those
up dieting
exercise
discipline
support system
exercise equipment even you know recipes
you know think of it that way that's a
real easy one because there's so much
out there uh also you can just follow
somebody else who's doing that and
figure out their subcategories exactly
and then underneath each one of those
tiers
just start brainstorming do a brain dump
what about
exercising
this this is the regimen i use uh this
is one uh one
program
what's that how to not injure yourself
how do you not injure yourself you know
how to what are some red flags at a gym
you know like you know all this kind of
stuff and for me it's like with
christian living it's like okay worship
and prayer and reading the bible and and
you know raising my family and all this
kind of stuff well what about that
raising my family like making sure i'm
leaving a legacy for my kids and making
sure that i'm taking care of them and
i'm not yelling at them or injuring them
or anything like that you know making
sure to my prayer time i'm focused on on
god and hearing from him and in the
bible reading the right way and so
you all of a sudden that's like 20
pieces of content like you just came up
with by sitting down and just and now
what i do is i keep a running list on
evernote i use evernote for just about
everything in my whole life and and i
have a running couple notebooks that are
just different categories of here's a
quick thought here's a quick thought i
do it more on the go now but if i'm ever
like really running dry i'll go do that
i'll go sit on my porch and i'll just
sit there and drink a cup of coffee or
i'll you know listen to some music and
i'll just start writing you know take in
this is not like an hour long process
it's a 15 minute 10 minute process take
a smoke break even if you're not a
smoker you know go take a smoke break at
work and go sit out in the parking lot
just sit there and just go okay
my my thing
is branding so in branding there's
design aesthetic there's language
there's consistency in marketing all
this type of stuff there's funnels
there's all sorts of things so it's like
you can break your big idea into
medium-sized ideas and then in those
medium-sized ideas are tons of different
things and here's the deal if you ever
run out sometimes you can just go back
and do stuff from the very beginning
like i've re-recorded different things
that i've done in the beginning because
a i got better equipment now
b i have a little bit more experience
behind the camera uh you know and a lot
of the people who saw that either forgot
about it or it's a whole different new
people that i'm reaching today
so don't be afraid of repetition
especially if it's good content and it
really it really matters to your brand
because
you every single time you post you're
going to reach about 60
of people that are brand new to you
they might have seen one other piece of
content from you you got your 40 that
are your regular followers and they're
not going to care either i mean you know
sometimes repetition is good because
even among them it's you got 100 people
who follow you maybe 30 of those people
see any given posts that you make
you know so it's okay to be repetitious
in fact sometimes that's really good for
your brand because it's a big idea that
you believe in you're going to be
passionate about and they're going to go
ah you know for you you've said this
before you know uh imperfect action is
you know better than no action or
something something like you're talking
about and taking in perfect action
taking imperfect action taking imperfect
action i've heard you say that probably
no less than 20 times but that doesn't
mean that i'm tired of you saying that
yeah or that you said it ad nauseum but
it really speaks to this is the big idea
that i that i got from jeremiah it was
big idea number one taking imperfect
action you know and i that's like i
should you should get like a tattoo
somewhere if you do tattoos
perfect action like right here but it's
like that's sort of that's okay i'm
gonna spell it too that'd be great yes
imperfect
like a little apostrophe m you know like
you know uh anyways but you know if
you're ever short on content ideas just
start there like just take get yourself
a nice place that's like
you know you might even
you might even go to a coffee shop and
just sit at a coffee table you know
whatever makes you know i was reading
this whole thing about you know your
brain and creativity if you get in the
same routine every single day you're
likely to lull your body and your brain
to sleep so sometimes i would take
different routes to school when i drop
my kids off at school i'd take different
routes even though i live like right
around the corner from it i'd go the
long super long way and double back just
by the time i got home i was a little
bit more awake and i could focus on
content creation it would come so much
easier than if i just
okay let me get in the car and go take
the kids and boom boom real quick and oh
my brain's asleep you know and so
sometimes just going to a coffee shop
can awaken that creativity going to a
nice vista awaken that creativity we're
not talking about hours 15 20 minutes
write yourself down
20 pieces of content that's 20 days
that's 20 days and then here's here's
the secret behind that when you talk
about multiple forms of content like
pictures and quotes and all this kind of
stuff
script out what you're doing
because now in two weeks
you can go back and watch your videos
from two weeks ago take your favorite
quote from that and that's your text
quote
for two weeks from now
you know what i mean like you're just
repurposing content and and if you're
skilled enough with that over time you
might even never have to think of new
content again just to repurpose you know
90 days ago
don't do that that's you know that's
lazy
you actually can do that i talked to a
social media guy he has like millions of
followers he says as long as it's over
90 days old or maybe six months yeah if
you are so busy that day it's okay to
take one or two of those old posts if it
did well repost it
and i've definitely done that especially
with quite a few of them like i was
thinking about that one day you know i
was thinking about this one post i did
and i was like ah
i need to do that again like why not it
was like my favorite bible verse
with a different outfit
absolutely yeah and then you you're
gonna say it a little differently you're
gonna you're gonna add something
something might come to you creatively
in the moment that you wished you would
have said back then or a comment that
someone made
might prompt you and responding to the
interactions that you get on your posts
that is a
wealth of content ideas how people
respond to your posts what they comment
on
your interaction with them tell me more
about that and they give you everything
that you can answer in your next post
hmm wow you know interacting with people
having meaningful conversations it
really demystifies all this because
you're just having conversations with
people yes it might be one way because
you're just looking into a camera at
first and it might take you a while to
get engagement and views and that's okay
just learn from it and keep going but
give yourself tons of at bats you and
you and rick taught me that give
yourself tons of at-bats you might not
hit a home run you might even not hit a
base hit but just try and keep trying
and keep trying and eventually you'll
get the reps in and you'll get better at
it
and you'll see some success that's
amazing and you know this episode has i
think for some people been
an advanced master class in social media
content i'm gonna probably add it as
like a bonus tell everybody who bought
my social media course they need to
watch this episode because it's like
it's like the the the next steps once
they learn the technical side like they
need to get this stuff i'm going to be
telling everybody they need to watch
this episode you've been dropping bombs
it's absolutely amazing i'm so thankful
to have you here one thing i was going
to ask you too you know i have a lot of
followers too that are also christians
a lot of them are
how have you found your faith and even
spending time with god affecting your
social media content creation so that is
like the first step in my day i i i set
my day up that way like where i
i've been waking up earlier um i've been
i get up i make a cup of coffee i have
this office fortune thankful so thankful
for this space that i come in here every
morning and i i spend time and i pray
and i worship and i read my bible before
i do anything else it sets the tone for
me and my life just to
it's like we give out of our first 10
the first fruits i give out of the first
fruits of my day
that's just a conviction i have some
people spend time with the lord at night
i i you know for me it's the day it's
how i start and and that honestly
even like in songwriting if i ever get
dry in songwriting i'll start singing
out scripture like for me that's the
source of my creativity it's just
spending time with god and so when i do
that it really quickens the old king
james is like quicken you know it like
it excites me it totally brings life
into my body and then i have purpose you
know one thing i found myself telling
somebody the other day the cool thing
about the story of the garden of eden
was that in that moment we think we find
this perfect um
this perfect meshing or
alignment of purpose
authority
and intimacy and adam has intimacy with
god he's walking with him day in in the
cool of the day he has purpose he's
given a task he's given something to do
tending the garden naming the animals
he's giving authority you're over all of
this and it's this
perfect alignment of these ideas so when
i start my day that way i feel like i'm
getting back to that original intent
that god has for me of being
perfectly aligned not perfect because
i'm not perfect but perfectly aligned
with intimacy purpose and authority and
so and i mean my authority too as well
is not having the self-doubt of am i
really supposed to do all the things
that i'm doing yes just get over that do
it like
no one has any more authority than
anyone else just just be who you are
like there's experts but you don't even
have to be an expert to do the thing
that you do
just do it with some degree of knowledge
and we're all figuring this thing out
along the way so you know life i mean
life you know what i'm saying so so what
i find is if i start my day that way it
really gives me permission out of that
place of intimacy with god to then have
purpose
be so filled with purpose throughout the
day and then have authority really
really believe what i say in what i do
is right um you know and and i receive
you know direction in that regard but
what i'm getting at is just not it's
like feeling confident feeling confident
in what you're supposed to do you know
and having purpose and then going back
to that place of intimacy too as well
every single morning and throughout the
day talking with the lord and asking him
for wisdom and strategies even before
this call i was saying lord give me
wisdom give me revelation give me the
words to say you said you would you said
you would give me words to say when i
stand before men you know i want to have
that i want you to speak through me so
that i can glorify you so that's that's
how i would say talk to christians
i love it
i absolutely love it this is great
this has been just a huge blessing for
me i hope this has been a blessing for
for you guys the listeners make sure
that you connect with david willis again
i'm going to put his his handle on the
screen it's uh david willis co
that's d-a-v-i-d-w-i-l-l-i-s-c-o
at david willis co on all platforms last
question i have for you what are your
top two or three favorite video games
oh um
it's been a long time since i've picked
up a video game yeah
this one's hard hang on you might
so titanfall 2
was
really big favorite of mine just because
all the controls felt so good and then
by extension i guess apex legends sort
of had the same
some similar structure to that but um i
would say that
oh man and um
i really liked the old age of empires
games me too
well a while back you could play them
online and do all that kind of stuff i
used to do that all the time like when i
was very young like oh the older ones
were like
15 20 years ago you know that's
when i played those last but uh
yeah i'm convinced you can actually
learn a lot about somebody's personality
if they like video games by what their
top games are it's actually very
interesting because that's cool that
draws you in
same with movies and stuff like that too
but video games is different because
it's like you know what do you like to
do and stuff like that i always enjoyed
those those games as well
when i was younger i like role-playing
games uh anything i can like
be the hero and and
kill people and stuff
usually with swords though and stuff
swords are magic stuff like that that's
the stuff i like so any game where i
have the choice to be a bad guy or a
good guy i totally cannot help myself
but be the good guy like me too i have
friends who are good i know
and they choose to be the bad guy at
video games like why it's so mean
totally so i i guess that's part of my
i'm an enneagram one enfj whatever all
the other stuff is in that same vein so
i'm like
i'm gonna have to be an altruistic guy
like throughout everything that i do and
so like i can't even like do the bad
thing in the video game
and i'm an enneagram three
oh okay
okay oh yeah that's why we we vibe
together i i think rick is also an enfj
as well but he's a oh okay but he's a
seven
mm-hmm oh wow that was like the
different personalities even
like the three of us there's such
similarities in in how we look at the
world from like the myers-briggs side
but like enneagram shows the differences
it's so cool
i love that when i first got turned onto
all that stuff with personality tests
first i was like oh no nothing's gonna
peg me like that you know
and then i start reading i was like yep
it yep
yep yep dang it you know totally
so it's really it's really funny
well david i'm i'm so glad that you were
on here i'm so glad that you reached out
and hey listen
is there anything else any final words
that you'd love to say just
encouragement to people
that that are they're they're getting
started
they hear me say you need to make social
media content but they're still they're
overwhelmed just a word of encouragement
before we go
i i love dave ramsey's quote he's
usually talking about finances but i
think it's kind of universally
applicable if you live like no one else
now then you'll live like no one else
later and i like the idea of saying you
know
i've spent a lot of my life
like maybe most of you two as well
making excuses for why i don't have this
my career hasn't gotten off the ground
i've not i released my first music like
really like this past fall like when i
started doing social media stuff and
i've been playing music and writing
music for 15 years
like
crazy why did i wait this long
so
there's no time like the present is the
adage but
the truth is
you're not going to change until you
hurt enough to change most people aren't
and i pray that you do change before you
have pain in your life you know because
it's so good to change to add something
new in your life because just like
abraham was called out of his comfort
zone into the promises that god had for
him in genesis 12 and 13 and 11 all this
type of stuff you he wasn't just for him
bible says that generations would be
blessed out of abraham the whole nation
would be blessed when you do something
cool and successful and you put yourself
out there even if you fail at one
business and then you use that to start
a new business or whatever
you're helping other people you're
bringing other people with you abraham
brought lot with him he brought his
whole family with him you're bringing
people with you and it's something so
cool and exciting when you do something
new something fresh and it blows up or
it gets successful that you can help
other people in your life you can bless
other people you are blessed to be a
blessing and that's not just some
catchphrase or some fortune cookie
wisdom but what it really means is that
what god does in you he's wanting to do
through you and so
don't hesitate quit hesitating this is
the most important time of your life by
that i mean right now
today you're not promised tomorrow you
got to forget about what happened
yesterday what are you doing with right
now so take the risk take the steps
start the thing
uh
it's not too late do it i love it so
good thank you david willis make sure
you guys go connect with him again at
david willis co on all platforms grow
your life everybody and we'll talk soon
have a good one